Guide to the Ira Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1960s-2000s; Series VI; 37
  - Photographs by Gerard Malanga, Ira Cohen and others of family, friends, Geoff Smith, Susi, Tango, Suzanna, Bobby, Penny Arcade, Isabella, Heather Louden, Coney Island, Malaysia, Thailand, Gilles' Party, 1980s-2000s (Box 130)
  - Photographs of the Medicine Shop, Dik Preston, Lakshmi, Raphael, Rose, Bisbee, Heather in a cat hat, Billy F., and envelopes, 2000s (Box 131)
  - Photographs signed by Ira Cohen and Ira Landgarten, 1970s-1990s (Box 132 (Oversize))
  - Photographs signed and unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1990s (Box 133 (Oversize))
  - Photographs unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1990s (Box 134 (Oversize))
  - Photographs signed and unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1980s (Box 135 (Oversize))
  - Photographs signed and unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1990s (Box 136 (Oversize))
  - Photographs signed and unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1990s (Box 137 (Oversize))
  - Photographs signed and unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1990s (Box 138 (Broadside))
  - Photographs signed and unsigned by Ira Cohen, 1970s-1990s (Box 139 (Broadside))
  - Unsigned portraits, 1980s-1990s (Box 140 (Oversize))
  - Unsigned portraits, 1980s-1990s (Box 141 (Oversize))
  - Unsigned portraits, 1980s-1990s (Box 142 (Oversize))
- Papers removed from printed material, undated; Series VII; 10
  This series consists of various papers removed from printed material that was removed from the collection for separate cataloging.
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 143)
    Includes correspondence from Jane Falk to Ira Cohen; "Crossing the Border," a choreography by Nadine Ganase; The Full Anthology Deck; correspondence from Jen-X; "Poems from the Akashic Record" proofs
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 144)
    Includes "Spirit" T-Shirt; hand printed posters by OP; Broadshirt Poetry Magazine T-Shirt; correspondence removed from "Longshot" vol. 21
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 145)
    Includes newsletters, correspondence, catalogs, playbills and other ephemera; bound photocopies of "God's Boot" by Brad Fox; envelope from "Revue Internationale pou Poésle Expérimentale" Numero 13; program from La MaMa E.T.C. presents "In Your Mind," a cabaret by Steve Buscemi and Mark Boone Junior; untitled poem removed from "Living On The Earth Spelling The Foul", by Robert Valenza.
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 146)
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 147)
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 148)
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 149)
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 150)
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 151)
  - Papers removed from printed material (Box 152)
- Artwork, 1970s-2000s; Series VIII; 10
  - Artwork, prints, and posters, 1970s-2000s (Box 153 (Oversize))
  - Artwork, prints, and posters, 1970s-2000s (Box 154 (Oversize))
  - Artwork, prints, and posters, 1970s-2000s (Box 155 (Broadside))
  - Paintings, 1980s (Box 156 (Broadside))
  - Kirke Wilson screen prints based on Ira Cohen photographs, 1980s (Box 157 (Broadside))
  - Kirke Wilson screen prints based on Ira Cohen photographs, 1980 (Box 158 (Broadside))
  - Kirke Wilson screen prints based on Ira Cohen photographs, 1980 (Box 159 (Broadside))
  - Drawings by Macneice, 1980s (Box 160 (Broadside))
  - Zellmer Phillips prints based on Ira Cohen photographs, 1980s (Box 161 (Broadside))
  - Paintings and drawings, 1970s-1980s (Box 162 (Oversize))
  - Drawings, paintings, notebooks, and correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 163)
  - Material printed on fiber paper, drawings, and notes, 1970s-2000s (Box 164)
  - Material printed on fiber paper, 1970s (Box 165 (Oversize))
  - Material printed on fiber paper, 1970s (Box 166 (Broadside))
  - Loose artwork by various artists, 1970s-2000s (Box 167 (Oversize))
  - Framed artwork, 1980s (Box 168 (Oversize))
  - Posters from poetry readings, art openings, and concerts, 1980s-2000s (Box 169 (Oversize))
  - Posters from poetry readings, art openings, and concerts, 1980s-2000s (Box 170 (Oversize))
  - Posters from poetry readings, art openings, and concerts, 1980s-2000s (Box 171 (Broadside))
  - Posters from poetry readings, art openings, and concerts, 1980s-2000s (Box 172 (Broadside))
  - Posters from poetry readings, art openings, and concerts, 1980s-2000s (Box 173 (Broadside))
- Objects, circa 1936, 1980s-2000s; Series IX; 10
  - Stickers, correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 174)
  - Rubber, metal, and wood stamps, 1990s-2000s (Box 175)
  - Rubber, metal, and wood stamps, 1990s-2000s (Box 176)
  - Rubber, metal, and wood stamps, 1990s-2000s (Box 177)
  - Rubber, metal, and wood stamps, 1990s-2000s (Box 178)
  - Knick-knacks, 1980s-2000s (Box 179)
  - Commercially made mask used in photographs of friends, knick-knacks, 1980s-2000s (Box 180)
  - Commercially made mask used in photographs of friends, knick-knacks, and camera lens, 1980s-2000s (Box 181 (Oversize))
  - Papier mache masked made from the faces of friends and counterculture figures, 1980s (Box 182)
  - Plaster castings of William S. Burroughs hand, Allen Ginsberg's face and Julian Beck's face, 1980s (Box 183)
  - Black Royal Portable Standard ("Model O") typewriter, circa 1936 (Box 184 (Art))
- Audiovisual materials, 1965-2000s; Series X; 34
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Footage of Paradise Now shot by Marty Topp and Ira Cohen, 1970s; 22 (Box 44)
  - Bob Dylan LP (Box 93 (Record album storage))
  - 13 audiocassettes, 2 45 rpm records, 2 VHS, 2 CD, 1 DVD (Box 94)
    - Films and videos produced by Professor James Bogan Performing Arts Department University of Missouri-Rolla, undated; YCALMSS625_0001; 1; 02:04:31 (Box 94, Item barcode 39002102318251)
      Chalk Up Another (4:53)
      Tom Benton's Missouri (28:26)
      Dreams of the Dark River (5:00)
      Song of the Evening Fishermen (3:50)
      The Hammock Variations (16:00)
      Color It Brazil (4:00)
      T-Shirt Cantata (12:00)
      "As Varicoes da Rede de Dormir" (15:50)
      Tom Benton's Missouri - Portuguese version (29:26)
      Sonho Do Rio Escuro (5:00)
    - Ira Cohen at Si La Antwerp, 1994-05-19; YCALMSS625_0002; 1; 01:08:39; Tape playback is of poor quality. It has been adjusted as best as possible. (Box 94, Item barcode 39002102318269)
  - 11 audiocassettes, 4 VHS, 2 CD, 3 DVD, 1 DVD-R (Box 95)
    - osseus labyrint, undated; YCALMSS625_0003; 1; 00:52:57 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002102318277)
    - The Living Theatre Emergency Mystic Fire Video, 1968; YCALMSS625_0004; 1; 00:32:10 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002102318285)
    - Money Machine 4 scenes, undated; YCALMSS625_0005; 1; 00:06:45 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002102318293)
    - "The Book of Logic" part 6 by Lionel Ziprin video by Clayton Patterson at Lionel's house, 1988-07-12; YCALMSS625_0006; 1; 02:04:28 (Box 95, Item barcode 39002102318301)
      Video by Clayton Patterson at Lionel's House
  - 9 audiocassettes, 1 VHS, 4 CD, 1 CD-R (Box 96)
    - Ira and Gerard M. Ira intro for "Hello Adelaide" film fest Art at Art Resources 3/6/3, undated; YCALMSS625_0007; 1; 01:01:23 (Box 96, Item barcode 39002102318319)
  - 46 reel-to-reel films, 1 audio reel (Box 97)
  - 18 video cassettes (Box 185)
    - Kid Gnaova Dances miscellaneous; Tape 1, number 1, undated; YCALMSS625_0008; 1; 00:22:36 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318327)
    - Untitled; Tape 1, number 2, undated; YCALMSS625_0009; 1; 00:22:53 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318335)
    - Untitled; Tape 1, number 4, undated; YCALMSS625_0010; 1; 00:22:50 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318343)
    - Untitled; Tape 1, number 5, undated; YCALMSS625_0011; 1; 00:22:45 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318350)
    - Untitled; Tape 1, number 6; also 1st part of Tape 3, number 1, undated; YCALMSS625_0012; 1; 00:22:51 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318368)
    - Gnaova Singer; Tape 2, number 1, undated; YCALMSS625_0013; 1; 00:21:53 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318376)
    - Marakech Street Scenes 1 tape 2; Tape 2, number 2, undated; YCALMSS625_0014; 1; 00:20:36 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318384)
    - Untitled; Tape 2, number 3, undated; YCALMSS625_0015; 1; 00:20:57 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318392)
    - Street Musicians; Tape 2, number 4, undated; YCALMSS625_0016; 1; 00:15:58 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318400)
    - Boiling Water Drinker Dances (Gnaova); Tape 2, number 5, undated; YCALMSS625_0017; 1; 00:22:57 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318418)
    - Untitled; Tape 2, number 6, undated; YCALMSS625_0018; 1; 00:16:35 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318426)
    - Untitled;Tape 3, number 1, undated; YCALMSS625_0019; 1; 00:23:03 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318434)
    - Marocco;Tape 3, number 2, undated; YCALMSS625_0020; 1; 00:22:52 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318442)
    - Seller Snake Charmer [General] Scenes;Tape 3, number 3, undated; YCALMSS625_0021; 1; 00:22:40 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318459)
    - Untitled; Tape 3, number 4, undated; YCALMSS625_0022; 1; 00:22:51 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318467)
    - Untitled;Tape 3, number 5, undated; YCALMSS625_0023; 1; 00:22:39 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318475)
    - Untitled; Tape 3, number 6, undated; YCALMSS625_0024; 1; 00:22:57 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318483)
    - Untitled;Tape 4, number 2, undated; YCALMSS625_0025; 1; 00:21:34 (Box 185, Item barcode 39002102318491)
  - 4 video cassettes, 1 DVD-R, 1985, 2000s (Box 186)
    - Acrobats Snake Charmers and Water Drinker; Tape 1, number 3, undated; YCALMSS625_0026; 1; 00:22:37 (Box 186, Item barcode 39002102318509)
    - Untitled; Tape 4, number 1, undated; YCALMSS625_0027; 1; 00:22:27 (Box 186, Item barcode 39002102318517)
    - Ira Cohen Marrakech?, undated; YCALMSS625_0028; 1; 01:02:19 (Box 186, Item barcode 39002102318525)
    - Quakebasket at 1st Planet Ira Morocco Tape II II(1) III(a), undated; YCALMSS625_0029; 1; 01:00:07 (Box 186, Item barcode 39002102318533)
    - Quakebasket at 1st Planet Ira Morocco Tape III(2) III(3) III(4), undated; YCALMSS625_0030; 1; 01:03:12 (Box 186, Item barcode 39002102318541)
  - 44 video cassettes, 1980s-2000s (Box 187)
    - Poetry reading at Spring Street China Club Valery and Ira video by Angelo and Jauuzzi, undated; YCALMSS625_0031; 1; 01:31:31 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318558)
    - Ira's birthday 1969, undated; YCALMSS625_0032; 1; 01:04:15 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318566)
    - Ira Cohen poetry tracing at the Pink Pony shot by Steve Ze[heutner], undated; YCALMSS625_0033; 1; 01:39:12 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318574)
    - KleurNET Ira Cohen Marina, undated; YCALMSS625_0034; 1; 00:08:17 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318582)
    - Ira at Home, 2002-06-11; YCALMSS625_0035; 1; 00:58:55 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318590)
      Ira, Love and Kisses [?]
    - Cocktails with Brookie (no sound); Ashes and Diamonds 1958 LP Andrzj Wadja; Witchcraft Through the Ages SLP, undated; YCALMSS625_0036; 1; 04:21:10 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318608)
    - Ira Cohen Anthony Perkins THS Columbia University, 1997; YCALMSS625_0037; 1; 00:31:31 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318616)
    - And Then He Kissed Me by Jo Ambroso, undated; YCALMSS625_0038; 1; 00:05:30 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318624)
    - Word/Play Poetry Lineages: Passing the Flame John Brandi and Ira Cohen Medicine Show, 2004-04-04; YCALMSS625_0039; 1; 01:33:34; Synchronized buzz in the audio cannot be removed. (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318632)
    - Ira Cohen in his underwear New York City; PAL, undated; YCALMSS625_0040; 1; 01:59:05 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318640)
    - Ira with Tower Recording at the Knitting Factory 50 minutes; Thurston Moore/Susan [?] 4 minutes, 2000-01-09; YCALMSS625_0041; 1; 01:03:28 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318657)
    - Conversation with Channer 8 hour potpourri, undated; YCALMSS625_0042; 1; 08:12:10; Tape was recorded in SLP mode. The quality is poor, but can be viewed. (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318665)
    - Ruigoord JL, 2003; YCALMSS625_0043; 1; 00:53:36 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318673)
    - Ira Cohen 2 London, undated; YCALMSS625_0044; 1; 00:46:21 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318681)
    - Ira Cohen New York City; SF Poetmuseum SS Kush Cloud House Poetry Archives, 2001-11-11; YCALMSS625_0045; 1; 01:02:24 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318699)
    - Various titles, undated; YCALMSS625_0046; 1; 02:03:37 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318707)
      Papillote; 10 min
      The Black Banana; 71 min
      Flora Extreme Unction; 12 min
      Memories of Jewish India; 10 min
      Tractor Safety Film; 12 min
      Yohanan Simon-Israeli Painter; 10 min
    - Ira Cohen at Duke Ellington Boulevard Jonathan Penton, 2002-06; YCALMSS625_0048; 1; 00:24:35 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318723)
    - Ira Cohen New York City; SF Poetmuseum SS Kush Cloud House Poetry Archives, 2001-11-11; YCALMSS625_0047; 1; 01:02:24; Duplicate; not digitized (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318715)
    - Ira Cohen New York City in his underwear, undated; YCALMSS625_0049; 1; 01:59:25 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318731)
    - CFEAS exhibition reception Yamaguchi Kenjiro "Bars": graphic art and ceramic sculpture, YCALMSS625_0050; 1; 00:41:11 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318749)
    - Reel of films and music; [illegible text]; Burning Man, undated; YCALMSS625_0051; 1; 00:14:40 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318756)
    - Ira reading Fish Drum Ondi, 2001-02; YCALMSS625_0052; 1; 01:28:20 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318764)
    - Ira Amsterdam, 2005; YCALMSS625_0053; 1; 00:54:35 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318772)
      Ira, The CD is just the audio of the video. The video is PAL system (European) so you will have to have it transferred to NTSC (US) to play it at home. The start of it is a bit messy as I was trying to adjust something in the camera at the time. It cuts and then it's a pretty smooth ride from there. Enjoy yourself watching and listening to yourself! Love, Benjamin
    - Tally Brown New York, undated; YCALMSS625_0054; 1; 01:42:20 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318780)
      (Please keep in mind, Tally did not like this film!)
    - Ira, undated; YCALMSS625_0055; 1; 01:12:47 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318798)
      9101
    - Ira Cohen and Aiden Andrew Dun Newcastle England, undated; YCALMSS625_0056; 1; 02:36:38; NTSC (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318806)
    - At Tagine: Jack Hirschman Agneta Falk Ira Cohen Saut El Ghorba, 2000-05-13; YCALMSS625_0057; 1; 02:03:44 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318814)
    - Ira Cohen "Playing for Real" 13 minutes The Lower East Side Biography Project, 2000; YCALMSS625_0058; 1; 00:16:08; This tape is in very bad condition. It exhibits tension problems. This is the best picture possible. (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318822)
    - iTVW Ira Cohen, 2001-08-18; YCALMSS625_0059; 1; 01:02:00 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318830)
    - Tagine tape 2 1 hour Ira Cohen and Louise L. Levi, 2002-11-20; YCALMSS625_0060; 1; 01:02:47 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318848)
      shot by Will Swofford
    - Ira Cohen Kush Cloud House, 2001-11-11; YCALMSS625_0061; 1; 01:04:57; Sync buzz in the audio. It cannot be removed. (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318855)
      SF Poetmuseum [SS] Kush
    - Mama London Corinna MacNeice, undated; YCALMSS625_0062; 1; 00:13:33 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318863)
      Dear Ira, Forgive the delay - Reid (Argos' bro) made his exit a couple of weeks ago after a seven-month battle w/ melanoma. He was buried in a sheet on the land... still contemplative here - death is a mysterious affair!... Anyway, I send you your [?] 'Mama London': should you think worth 'netting' or whatever I can make SVHS copy (better quality). Much Love Ira, Corinna
    - Poems and essays by Johnny Dolphin. Reading at Caravan of Dreams, 1992-01; YCALMSS625_0063; 1; 00:49:02 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318871)
      To Ira, From Johnny - Hope you are well! [?]
    - Corso Memorial at St. Mark's Ira Cohen; Sheri Langerman; Roger Richards; Marty Matz; Penny Arcade; Patti Smith for [?]-PEACE Laki, 2001-04-26; YCALMSS625_0064; 1; 00:46:07 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318889)
    - Hoboken's best Ira at Maxwell's with P. Robinson and T. Barnest, undated; YCALMSS625_0065; 1; 01:26:39 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318897)
    - Ira Cohen San Francisco SS Kush Poetmuseum Cloud House, 2001-11-11; YCALMSS625_0066; 1; 01:04:19; This tape could be a duplicate. (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318905)
    - Poetry at gunpoint G.G. [?]stein Fishdrum Suzi Winson at Medicine Show; Ira Michael Rothenberg, 2001-03-16; YCALMSS625_0067; 1; 01:54:04 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318913)
      Hi Ira, Suzi asked me to send this to you. Claudia
    - Conversations 1 Channer Time Warner Cable NYS. 1st guest: Ira Cohen 1999 July 23' 2nd guest: Monroe Rosenthal and Lenni Brenner 1996 August 30, undated; YCALMSS625_0068; 1; 02:00:21 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318921)
    - Kings With Straw Mats: a film by Ira Cohen, undated; YCALMSS625_0069; 1; 01:15:08 (Box 187, Item barcode 39002102318939)
  - 9 video cassettes, 1980s-2000s (Box 188)
    - Ono Kazno and NHK Yoshito, undated; YCALMSS625_0070; 1; 01:16:52 (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102318947)
    - Ira Cohen and Tribal Warning Theater Media Gallery Cloud House Poetry Archive Kush, 1988-07-19; YCALMSS625_0071; 1; 02:04:29 (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102318954)
    - Copy of "Invasion of Thunderbolt Pagoda", undated; YCALMSS625_0072; 1; 00:23:33 (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102318962)
    - Ira Cohen ATP-UCLA Royce Hall l'heure wendy, 2002-03-14; YCALMSS625_0073; 1; 00:27:53 (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102318970)
      Ira - per [your] request - video of [your] reading at ATP - Rock on, Thurston
    - Spider Dance Ira in Europa, undated; YCALMSS625_0074; 1; 00:55:53 (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102318988)
    - Ira Cohen Pan Panjandrum Kush and his song camel Cloud House San Francisco Poetmuseum, 2001-11-11; YCALMSS625_0075; 1; 01:06:16 (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102318996)
      Cloud House Poetry Archives SS Kush
    - "Hello Adelaide" Ira and Gerald, 2003; YCALMSS625_0076; 1; 00:39:43; The tape is in poor condition. (Box 188, Item barcode 39002102319002)
  - 47 VHS, 1 mini video cassette, 1986-1999 (Box 189)
    - Orfeo at the Kitchen with 50 seconds of photos at the end, 1995-02-24; YCALMSS625_0077; 1; 01:40:21 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319010)
      video by Tom Wright
    - El Topo, undated; YCALMSS625_0078; 1; 02:04:16; The tape is in very poor condition. The tape has been tried in every machine. The cartridge was worked on as well, but the tape still breaks up. This is a commercial film. (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319028)
    - Kumbh Mela-Hardwar produced by Ira Cohen. Rough cut part 1 Video: Ira Landgarten and Ira Cohen, 1986; YCALMSS625_0079; 1; 01:21:46 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319036)
    - Ira Cohen Kumbla Mela Presentation Syracuse University. Tape by Roxanne Gupta, undated; YCALMSS625_0080; 1; 01:15:33 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319044)
    - Orfeo by Angus MacLise. Video by George Gilson, undated; YCALMSS625_0081; 1; 01:36:47 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319051)
    - Orfeo at the Kitchen by Angus MacLise, 1995-02-24; YCALMSS625_0084; 1; 01:47:28 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319085)
    - Orfeo by Angus MacLise. Video by George Gilson, undated; YCALMSS625_0085; 1; 01:35:54 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319093)
    - Tape for Ira Cohen: The Whirling Ecstasy and Aquarian Rushes, 1973; 1970; YCALMSS625_0086; 1; 00:57:33 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319101)
      1. The Whirling Ecstasy (1973)
      2. Aquarian Rushes (1970)
    - Paradise Now, undated; YCALMSS625_0087; 1; 00:47:02 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319119)
    - Rockers (For Preview Purposes Only), undated; YCALMSS625_0088; 1; 01:39:49 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319135)
    - Ira Cohen video by Clayton Patterson, 1989-08-22; YCALMSS625_0089; 1; 02:03:42 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319143)
    - Love Lion tape 2, 1991-08-16; YCALMSS625_0090; 1; 02:03:31 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319150)
    - Abbie's Yahrzeit, 1996-1997; YCALMSS625_0091; 1; 02:24:29 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319168)
      1) Anarchia Forum: 4/17/97
      2) A Forum: 4/24/97
      3) A Forum: 5/1/97
      4/ A Propoganda Variety Hour: 4/3/96
      5) "Majoon" from Events: 6/28/97
      6) A Forum: 5/29/97 (partial) Allen G. memories
    - Antal Isnan: Varnati Vagoyynan, undated; YCALMSS625_0092; 1; 00:47:18 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319176)
    - Tape #0 Ira's Arrival, undated; YCALMSS625_0093; 1; 01:56:53 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319184)
    - Tape #1 Ira meets Budapest, undated; YCALMSS625_0094; 1; 01:43:10 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319192)
    - Tape #3, 1998-12-28; YCALMSS625_0095; 1; 00:52:44 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319200)
    - Untitled, undated; YCALMSS625_0096; 1; 01:44:13 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319218)
    - For Ira: Candy, undated; YCALMSS625_0097; 1; 01:53:38 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319226)
      A printed review of the movie is attached to the tape.
    - Ira Cohen poetry reading and photos by George Gilson Museum Channel, 1993-12; YCALMSS625_0098; 1; 00:49:36 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319234)
    - Ira Cohen at The Lab San Francisco by Steve Harlow, 1989-06-24; YCALMSS625_0099; 1; 00:58:55 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319242)
    - Orfeo by Angus MacLise. Video by George Gilson Apt. 8L, undated; YCALMSS625_0100; 1; 01:35:37 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319259)
      At the Kitchen
    - Kings With Straw Mats last version, 1997-12; YCALMSS625_0101; 1; 01:09:43 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319267)
    - KAM America Paul Bowles/Ira's Bat Story tape #2, 1998-03-31; YCALMSS625_0102; 1; 01:21:22 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319275)
    - Ira Cohen at DCA (Dundee Contemporary Arts Scotland), 2003-10; YCALMSS625_0103; 1; 01:02:30 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319283)
      Ira's 'Thunderbolt Pagoda' with music by Acid Mathers --- Temple
      'Kill Your Timid Notions'
      Ira reading with 'Kings with Straw Mats' - guitar music by Dave Keenan, filmed by Heather Troy
    - Ira Cohen Curfew, 1994; YCALMSS625_0104; 1; 00:24:55; PAL, no sound This video was made without sound. (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319291)
      copyright: Hanzel and Gretzel. Brussels 1994
    - Changing Planes Judith Melina Hannon Renikov Ira Cohen New York City at the Pink Pony, 2002-05-29; YCALMSS625_0105; 1; 02:03:34; Duplicate of YCALMSS625_0264 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319309)
    - Dragon Dance Lucia Hwong, undated; YCALMSS625_0106; 1; 00:53:00; The movie "Go Tell It to the Mountain" follows at 00:08:32. (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319317)
    - Fire Visits Ira, 1996-03; 1; 02:13:18 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319325)
    - Kazuko Shiraishi with Yoshito Ono Sayoko Yamaquichi Aomoriken dr. Eitethu Hayashi, 1998-07-19; YCALMSS625_0108; 1; 00:25:24 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319333)
    - Flame's Follies created and edited by Flame Schon, undated; YCALMSS625_0109; 1; 00:24:37; This is the same as YCALMSS625_0252. Keep the best one. (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319341)
    - Ira Cohen poet; Dharmaware Woodstock NY, 1999-07-30; YCALMSS625_0110; 1; 01:03:49 (Box 189, Item barcode 39002102319358)
      Letter from White Buffalo Multi-Media dated 1999-09-14:
      Dear Ira, We enjoyed your presence at Dharmaware as well as the opportunity to hear your poetry and see that amazing film - wow, what a rarity. Someone recently mentioned you'd like a copy of the video we shot that night, so here you go - unedited - no tripod, just a documentation we thought would fit in the Woodstock Museum archives. If you need any of it in any format, the original was done on DV format, so it's gigital and ready to go anywhere. Looking forward to your poetry again. Peace Brother, [?]